This leads me to the general study of Conditional independence
这使我对贝叶斯网络中条件独立开展更广泛的研究
in Bayes Networks that works often called D-Separation or Reachability.
通常称为分隔定理或可达性
D-Separation is best studied by so called Active Triplet's and Inactive Triplet's.
分隔定理通过积极三元组和消极三元组进行研究
We have Active Triplet's render
我们认为积极三元组解释了
variables dependent and Inactive Triplet's render them independent.
依赖的变量 消极三元组解释了独立的变量
Any chain of three variables like this makes the initial and final variable dependent,
任何像这样的变量都会使初始变量和最终变量具有依赖性
if all variables are known.
如果所有变量是已知的
However, if the central variable is known that it's behind the conditioning bar,
然而 如果已知中间的变量位于后面
then this variable and this variable become independent.
那么这两个变量是相互独立的
So, if you have a structure like this and
如果你有个这样的结构
it's "cut off" by a known variable in the middle,
它被中间的已知变量”切断”了
that separates or d
分隔了
separates the left variable from the right variable and it will become independent.
左边和右边的变量 就会变得相互独立
Similarly, any structure like this
同样 像这样的结构
renders the left variable and the right variable dependent,
解释了左边和右边的变量相互依赖
unless, the center variable is known,
如果中间的变量是已知的
in which case the left and right variable become independent.
左边和右边的变量相互独立
Another Active Triplet's now requires knowledge
另一个积极三元组现在需要了解
of a variable.This is the explain away case.
变量 这是解去的例子
If this variable is known for any reason it will be converted into a single variable,
如果不论什么原因 这个变量都是已知的 这个可以转化为单一变量
then this variable and this variable here become dependent.
那么这两个变量是相互依赖的
Contrast this to the case that all variable is now unknown.
与这个相反的是所有变量都是未知的
A situation like this means that this variable
例如这种情况表明左边
on the left and on the right are actually independent.
和右边的变量实际上相互独立
In a single final example,
在最后这个例子中
we also get dependence if we have
如果我们出现下列情形
the following situation and direct successor of a conversion variable is known.
转化变量的直接后继是已知的
So it is sufficient if a successor of these variables is known,
所以如果这些变量的后继是已知的 它就是充分的
the variable itself does not have to be known.
变量本身可能不是已知的
And the reason is if you know this guy over
因为如果你知道这里的情况
here we need to get knowledge of this guy over here and,
我们需要知道这里的情况
by virtue of that, the case over here essentially applies.
通过这个 这里的情况才能得要应用
iF YOU look at those rules,
如果你观察这些规则
Those rules allow you to determine for any Bayes Network
这些规则可以让你
whether variables are dependent or not dependent given the evidence you have.
根据你已有证据 确定任何贝叶斯网络中变量是否相互独立 还是相互依赖
If you color the notes dark for which you do have evidence,
如果你把这些有证据的注释涂成黑色
then you can use these rules to understand whether
那么你就可以使用这些规则去理解
any two variables are condition dependent or not.
任意两个变量是否相互依赖
So let me ask you for
那么我要提问
this relatively complicated Bayes Network the following questions: is F independent of A,
对于这个相对复杂的贝叶斯网络 F 是否独立于 A
is F independent of A given D, is F independent of A given G and is F independent
F 是否独立于 A|D F 是否独立于 A|G
of A given H?
F 是否独立于 A|H
Please mark your answer as you see fit.
请选择合适的答案